Hey everyone, thank you all so much for
the support in the last couple videos.
It really means a lot. I also make music
on the side, so if you want to check it
out, the links in the description. No
pressure at all, but I really appreciate
it. If you're in the hotel doing a
meeting, and most of the meetings are
going to be either in a hotel or in a
car, right? The more sensitive sources,
you're going to meet in the car [music]
and then just keep driving around. But
in a hotel, if they start banging on
your door, rip off your clothes and
[music] jump into bed, both of you, cuz
you're going to be gay for a minute. So
when they finally break down the door,
they're like, "Oh [__] [music] we
thought you were meeting because we
thought you were CIA and you Oh my god,
no, you're just gay and then everybody's
okay." And a vulnerability can mean a
lot of different things. Maybe he just
really, really loves his kids.
That can be a vulnerability because then
that allows me to say, "I see how much
you love your kids. I know you want your
kids to go to the best schools. I can
literally get your kid into Harvard and
I'll pay for it, too, by the way. And he
says, "Well, what do you want in
exchange?" Well, I want the plans to
that new Russian tank. I'd really like
to get a peek at it. Another
vulnerability would be, you know, maybe
the guy's uh wife has are the Iranians
are a threat to the United States. He
said, "Of course not. They don't even
have a missile capable of reaching the
United States." But that's not the
issue. The issue is, are they a threat
to Israel? And everybody knows cuz
Benjamin Netanyahu says it every 15
seconds that Iran is a an existential
threat to Israel. But guess what? Israel
is an existential threat to Iran.
>> My colleague explained it in [music]
great detail. And a lot of these
techniques are not torture. Right? If I
grab you by the lapels and say,
>> "Dog on you and answer my questions."
>> That's not torture. [music] Or the the
first one was called the belly slap. uh
or the attention slap was another way
they call it where I
>> smack you in the belly, makes a cracking
sound. Maybe it leaves a handprint.
It's a [music] little bit embarrassing.
That's not torture.
>> But then it graduated quickly to things
like waterboarding, which everybody
knows about. But there were techniques
that were [music] that were in my view
that were worse than waterboarding. Like
for example, there was the cold cell.
>> So they strip [music] you naked. They
chain you to an eyebolt in the ceiling.
>> So you can't you can't lay or kneel or
sit or anything. and you can't get
comfortable in any way. And
>> [music]
>> um they they chill the cell to 50° F
>> and then every hour somebody [music]
comes in and throws a bucket of ice
water on you.
>> Oh, but we killed [music] people with
that technique. The Justice Department
never said we could kill people. And
when we would kill people, [music]
>> at least two with that technique that
that
admitted to from hypothermia.
>> Well, we have a special guest that's
going to come [music] to the party
tonight. And then Joe Biden comes. He
was vice [music] president at the time.
So Biden comes and Biden was exactly the
opposite of Jerry. Biden's standing at
the at the entrance to the [music]
backyard or the sideyard. He goes,
"Hey." Like this. Everybody's like,
"Hey, Mr. Vice President. [music] Good
to see you." So he comes down and um
starts shaking hands with everybody one
at a time. Great [music] eye contact. Uh
hi Joe Biden. Tell me your name again.
You know that kind of thing. I said,
"Mr. Vice President, we've met a number
of times. You probably don't remember
me. I'm from Newcastle, Pennsylvania. My
dad was best friends with Angelo [music]
Sans." He goes, "Angelo Sans from
seventh grade?" And I said, "Yeah,
you're best friend from seventh grade."
He says, "I do remember you. We talked
about Angelo as a taxi driver in Las
Vegas now." I said, "That's right. He is
a taxi driver. Great memory." I said,
"That conversation was 15 years ago."
And then he says to the guy next to me.
"I remember [music] you.
>> I don't like you."
>> And he looks at Carrie and Carrie just
[music] like like I don't like him
either. And they walk away. I said to
the guy, "What the fuck?"
>> He said, "Biden [music] has hated me
since I told him in a memo that we
should pull out of Afghanistan."
>> I get in at 7:00 in the morning. He had
something called a trunk line [music]
where the unclassified phones in the
office were connected to a [music]
Washington exchange. So even though I'm
in Pakistan, I've got a 202 number and
[music] I I can dial a 202 number like a
local call. So I would get in before
everybody else and I would always call
my then girlfriend, my post divorce
girlfriend who became my second wife.
[music] She was a senior CIA officer. So
um
[music] I would always end our
conversations by saying, "Okay, love you
and hang up." Yeah.
>> And one of [music] the old-timers, there
were seven old men who worked for me.
They were all like very senior senior
intelligence service level officers. All
of them had been at least director of
near eastern operations. One of them had
been the deputy director of the CIA. And
they all volunteered to come back as
contractors after 911 just for patriotic
reasons. [music] But if you're a
contractor, you can't have a management
position. So they worked for me, which
is
>> that must have been interesting.
>> I learned more from [music] those guys
in 6 months than I learned in the rest
of the entirety of my career. But
anyway, one of them [music] heard me
finish the call and hang up. And he
says, "So, are there wedding bells in
the future?" [music] And I said, "Oh, I
don't know. I just got divorced and I'm
kind of afraid of being a two-time
loser." And he says, "Two time loser."
Jim, how many times have you been
married? He [music] says, "Four for me."
Dave, how many times have you been
married? I got five. Bill, how many
times you've been married? Three. And he
says, "And I got four."
>> And she had a she had a TV on and one of
the towers of the World Trade Center was
burning. And I said, "What happened to
the World Trade Center?" And she said,
"A plane flew into it."
>> And I naively said,
>> "You know, that happened once before
>> in 1932.
A bomber flew into the Empire State
Building,
>> but it was really foggy then. It's so
crystal clear today. Like, how can you
not see that you're flying into the
World Trade Center?" And just as I said
those words, the
>> the second plane hit.
>> And then she turned to me. I was
standing behind her. She turned to me
and she said,
>> "Did you see that?"
>> Or did I imagine it? And I ran back to
my office and I
>> said, "Guys, two planes just hit both
towers of the World Trade Center. I
think we're under attack."
>> So everybody ran back up to the front
office. Now, Kofheer's office had TVs
mounted above the door like CNN, MSNBC,
Fox, BBC, Russian, Iranian, whatever,
Chinese, and um and they were all
starting to switch over to a live feed,
>> silence.
>> I mean, there were, you know, 150, 200
people just standing there staring at
the TVs in silence.
And then finally somebody shouts, "Will
somebody please lead?"
>> And then Kofheer snapped back into, you
know, real life and said,
>> "You uh go to the director's office. You
go to security. You talk to this guy.
You
>> um finally a cop came in to the to the
office and said, "We're evacuating
headquarters. Everybody get out."
>> Nobody budged.
And then an hour later he came back and
said, "If you don't evacuate,
>> you'll be arrested." Which they meant.
>> So, I mean, talk about chaos.
>> We all evacuated.
>> Um, I got about halfway home. I lived
about I lived about five or six miles
from headquarters. I got about halfway
and I just couldn't get any closer to my
place. So,
>> I just abandoned my car on the side of
the highway. ituaries.
>> Does torture work?
>> No. See, and that's the biggest thing.
>> Even if you think, well, you know, these
guys are really bad. They mean us harm.
They're murderers, mass murderers. Okay,
fine. It doesn't work.
That's why, you know, after I left the
agency, I went to the Senate Foreign
Relations Committee. I was the senior
investigator there, and I I was working
for John Kerry, and his office in the
Russell Senate office building was
directly next to John McCain's. And
every single time McCain would see me,
he would go out of his way to come and
shake my hand and say, "Hi, John. How
are you?" I'd say, "I'm great, Senator.
How are you doing? Good to see you
again." And finally, Carrie said to me
one day, "Why don't you and McCain get a
room or something?" And I said, "No." I
said, "We have a connection over torture
because he knows that I'm right. He
knows because he lived it. They tortured
him and he gave them all shit."
They said, "Who are the people in your,
you know, battalion or platoon or
whatever?" And then he just named the,
you know, uh, I had gone bankrupt
because of the legal fees. I actually
still owe my attorneys $1,150,000
that they'll never see. I'll never have
that money to pay them. Said [music] the
orders are to take them alive. No
shooting.
>> And I was looking at the Pakistanis when
I said this.
>> No shooting. Of course, they just opened
fire,
>> which began [music] by using
um experimentally. What the CI did was
they they [music] started by dosing
their own employees without telling
them.
>> Let's see what happens. See what they
say. See how it feels. You know, see if
we can control them. See if
>> we can plant memories that [music]
didn't actually happen.
>> And then they decided, no, it's not a
good idea to dose our own people.
>> Let's just dose strangers out in public.
And one of them said, "That junk Kiryaku
from the American embassy, he is such a
nice guy." And then another one said,
"You know what? Nobody's that nice. He's
he's pretending to be nice
>> so that we'll drop our guard."
>> Okay.
>> He's probably working against us, which
I wasn't.
>> So, they chose the worst possible
surveillance guy.
>> Oh, no.
>> To just check me out and see what I was
doing when I wasn't with them. And I
spotted him immediately. and I was going
to kill him. [laughter] And if I hadn't
told the general that afternoon that I
had spotted the surveillance and that I
was going to kill the guy, he'd be in
the ground. Three minutes after the cop
warned me about people coming into my
room unannounced, these two guys just
walk in, boldly just walk in. I jump up.
I
>> put my fist up. I go, "What do you
want?"
>> One of them has a swastika [music] on
his neck. It took up his entire neck. It
came up onto his face. The other one had
>> [__] you tattooed on his eyelids.
>> So I go, "What [music] do you want?" And
and the the swastika guy says, "You the
new guy?" I said, "Yeah, so and he says
>> you a fag."
>> I said, "No, I'm not a fag." He said,
>> "You a rat?" I said,
>> I said, "No, I didn't have anybody else
in my case. I'm not a rat." And he says,
"You a cho?"
>> I go, "I don't know what that word
means." He goes,
>> "Chomo, child molester."
>> I said, "No, I'm not a child molester."
And he goes, "Okay, you could sit with
the Aryans in the cafeteria." And I was
like, "Oh,
>> I guess I'm with the Aryans now."
>> Oh, grand. [music] Yeah. And then the
guy across the hall from me was the boss
of the Banano family.
>> I said, "Baghdad? [music]
>> Where exactly in Baghdad?"
>> I said, "If you hold on a second, I'll
look up the address." So I looked it up.
[music] I gave him the address. He
>> says, "Thank you." And he hangs up the
phone. 8 hours later, we fired 47 cruise
missiles [music] into Iraqi intelligence
service headquarters.
>> But by then, it was the [music] middle
of the night in Baghdaddy
>> and we killed the janitor.
>> Life is good. I'm about to clock out,
man.
This can't be how I go. [music]
>> It's not even you. I know.
>> CIA listen through our phones and laptop
[music] cameras.
>> Yes,
>> I hate to say it. They can uh take over
your smart television [music] and turn
the speaker into a microphone
>> so that they can listen to what's being
said in the room even when the TV is
turned off.
[music]
>> [music]
>> Heat. Heat.